smallhd.com 2019-03-28

# SmallHD LLC Privacy Policy

As part of The Vitec Group plc, SmallHD observes all applicant statutory data protection requirements and is aware of the fact that particularly sensitive handling of all personal data sent to the Vitec Group plc or any of its subsidiaries by the users is highly important to them. With this privacy policy, SmallHD, as part of the Vitec Group plc, would like to inform you about how we process your personal data. 

##### Data Controller: Who we are 

As a subsidiary of The Vitec Group plc, we sell our products and provide services to our customers throughout the world. SmallHD LLC is the data controller for your information. 

### Personal Data We Collect And How We May Use It

##### Introduction

  * Among other things, personal data is understood to mean information such as your name, address, e-mail address, and any other information that may identify you. We collect personal data only if, only to the extent that, and only for the purposes for which you provide us with this data of your own accord, for example, within the framework of a registration or sale. More specifically, we use your personal data for advertising purposes only if you have expressly given us your consent to do so. Your personal data will not be passed on to third parties without your express consent. Only within the framework of applicable legislation, or if we are obligated to do so by a court decision, shall personal data be transmitted to government institutions and authorities entitled to receive information.

  * Insofar as we commission third parties to fulfill individual tasks and services for us, their access to your personal data is limited to the extent necessary for the fulfillment of their tasks. These service providers are obligated to process your personal data in accordance with this privacy policy and applicable data protection laws.

##### What information we collect

  * ###### From our customers

    * We will collect personal information including name and contact details, such as address, email and phone number; also, with your explicit permission, certain pieces of sensitive information. 

    * We collect details of ethnicity for diversity and monitoring purposes. 

    * Financial information such as bank and direct debit requests together with subscription history will be maintained.

  * ###### Employees

We will collect all personal information required to comply with employment legislation, including, where necessary, sensitive information. This may include medical information and where additionally appropriate we will perform a criminal record search. To prevent discrimination, and ensure diversity, we shall request information from the Data Subject on religion, sexuality and ethnicity. 

  * ###### CCTV

In order to prevent and detect crime, and to ensure the safety of our customers and staff, we operate CCTV systems at our various locations. These cameras record footage in real-time and are operated and controlled by our own staff; monitoring and recording does not take place in any changing room and toilet areas. 

  * ###### Cookies

Anonymous user data is recorded when visiting our website, please see the section on cookies and Google Analytics below. No data is purchased or shared with any third parties. 

##### Children

We will not deliberately establish contact with children under 18 years of age, or 14 years of age in Korea, or collect their personal data. Our website is not directed at children and is not intended for collecting children's data. If you believe that we have mistakenly or inadvertently collected such information via our website, please contact us via the address provided below, so that we can immediately delete this data from our servers. 

Parents and guardians should be actively involved in their children's Internet and cell phone usage. 

### Why we need your information 

On _SmallHD.com_ , personal data is collected in order to perform various transactions such as:

  * Product or service orders, activations, and registrations: we need your information to fulfill our obligations under purchase agreements or service orders. Personal and financial information is essential to manage ongoing subscriptions and payments.

  * Creation of profiles and verification of users: we need your information to ensure you are the person creating a profile.

  * Requests for information: we need your information to ensure you are the person requesting information from us.

  * Marketing or support subscriptions: by understanding customers' interests and preferences we can provide our valued customers with targeted communications (direct mail) and concessions and other additional benefits. Personal and financial information is essential to manage ongoing subscriptions and payments. 

  * Participation in contests or surveys: we need your information to contact you if you win a prize or if we need to follow up on a survey.

  * Human resources, payroll and finance: To comply with employment legislation and ensure that all staff working within the organization are qualified, competent, vetted and receive ongoing training. 

The collection of personal data is carried out via Google Analytics which is an automated marketing tool that manages campaigns and analyzes client interests. Google complies with the requirements of the EU General Data Protection Regulations. 

For more information about this, go to <https://privacy.google.com/businesses/compliance/>

### How we process your Information or share it 

We will only use your personal information for the purpose for which it was given, we will not keep it for longer than is necessary and will destroy the information securely according to our formal retention policy. 

Unless a valid reason exists to retain longer, customer records are usually deleted 12 months after their subscription has expired. And all other records are retained for 7 years after the last official action. Job application files for unsuccessful applicants are destroyed after 12 months of the decision being made. 

In order to process orders, payments and financial transactions we use trusted and authorized secure third-party websites. Personal or sensitive information is not held or shared with third parties. 

We share information with our subsidiaries and affiliates to help us provide our services or conduct data processing on our behalf. 

#### Where we store your information 

Your personal information will be hosted securely within the United States. We share information with our subsidiaries and affiliates to help us provide our services or conduct data processing on our behalf. For example, we may process or store information in the United Kingdom on behalf of our international subsidiaries and affiliates. If we transfer your information to a data processor, for example, an email broadcast company to assist us in keeping you up-to-date with announcements, news and information, and they are located outside of the United States, we shall take all reasonable steps to ensure that your information is protected as if we hosted it ourselves. 

The Business Management Software that our company uses is **NetSutie (by Oracle)**. This system is used to retain all business related information and is a secure cloud based source. For any further information you can review NetSuite's privacy policy here: <http://www.netsuite.com/portal/privacy.shtml>

##### Marketing, Consents and Permissions

Via our newsletter, we inform you about our company, our services, and workshops. If you want to receive the newsletter, we require you to provide a valid e-mail address as well as information allowing us to verify that you are the owner of the specified e-mail address, or that its holder agrees to receive the newsletter. Further data is not collected. This data is only used to send the newsletters and will not be passed on to third parties. Upon subscription to the newsletter, we store your IP address and the date of the subscription. This only serves as proof in case a third party abuses an e-mail address and subscribes to the newsletter without the knowledge of the entitled party. You have the right to withdraw, amend or change your consent for data storage and storage of the e-mail address as well as its use for sending the newsletter at any time. You may do this via a link at the end of each individual newsletter itself or by contacting us, using the contact details provided below. 

##### Server Log Files

When you visit this website, the web server automatically records log files that cannot be attributed to any person in particular. This data includes, for instance, the browser type and version, the operating system used, the referrer URL (previously visited website), the IP address of the requesting computer, the access date and time of the server request, and the file request of the client (file name and URL). This data is only collected for the purpose of statistical analysis. The better we understand your wishes, the faster you can find the desired information on our webpages. The collected data is not passed on to third parties, neither for commercial nor non-commercial purposes. 

##### Integration of Social Network Plug-ins 

On SmallHD.com social network plug-ins may be integrated on individual pages (e.g., Like button, Share button). Social networks include Facebook, YouTube, or Twitter. When accessing a page on SmallHD.com containing such a plug-in, your browser establishes a connection to this social network. The content of the plug-in (the button) is then provided by the servers of this social network. In principle, these servers can thus track your visit to this page (in some cases including by means of cookies created during your visits to this social network).

If you click on the plug-in and are simultaneously logged in to the social network, data might be sent to this social network by your browser, and the social network may associate it with your user account. To find out what data is sent in the process and how the social network handles it, please refer to the privacy notices of the respective social network. These will also offer information regarding different settings for protecting your privacy. If you are not logged in, you are usually given an opportunity to log in or register and create a user account. 

If you wish to prevent your social network from collecting data about you, you can log out before and delete any cookies of this provider. If you do not have an account with a social network, no data is transmitted. 

##### Cookies and Website Tracking

On this website, we use analysis systems which serve to measure and analyze the visits to our website. We use your IP address with a view to collecting data, including about the pages visited on SmallHD.com, your browser, and your computer.

In addition, cookies are also issued. A cookie is a small file that is stored on your computer when you visit a website. If you visit the website again, the cookie indicates that this is a repeated visit. The cookie contains a unique number and, in some cases, a date. The cookie contains no personal information. The cookie is not suitable for identifying you on third-party websites, including the websites of the analytics providers.

You can configure your browser so that acceptance of cookies is, in principle, denied or you are notified before a cookie is stored. For more information, see the user manual of your Internet browser. Alternatively, you can visit the website <https://www.aboutcookies.org/>, where you will find step-by-step instructions on how to control and delete the cookies in most browsers. We do not use IP addresses or cookies to personally identify you. We use the systems with a view to increasing the efficiency of our website and marketing. When you use this website, cookies may possibly also be stored on your PC or other terminal by third-party providers. You can prevent the setting of these cookies by disabling acceptance of third-party cookies in your Internet browser. 

##### Google Analytics

This website uses Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google Inc. ("Google"). Google Analytics uses what are called "cookies" - text files that are stored on your computer and enable an analysis of your use of the website. The information generated by the cookie regarding your use of this website is generally transmitted to and stored on a Google server in the U.S. However, if IP anonymization is activated on this website, your IP address is first abbreviated by Google within member states of the European Union or in other states party to the Agreement on the European Economic Area. Only in exceptional cases will the entire IP address be transmitted to and abbreviated on a Google server in the USA. Google will use this information on behalf of the operator of this website to analyze your use of the website, to compile reports about website activities and to provide further services related to the use of the website and the Internet to the website operator. The IP address transmitted by your browser in the context of Google Analytics is not associated with any other data held by Google. You can prevent cookie storage by selecting the appropriate settings in your browser software; however, please note that, in that case, you may not be able to use all features of this website to their full extent. Additionally, you can also prevent Google from collecting the data created by the cookie and related to your use of the website (including your IP address) as well as from processing this data by downloading and [INSTALLING](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en-GB) the browser plug-in available.

You can find more information about this [HERE](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en-GB) or on this [PAGE](http://www.google.com/analytics/learn/privacy.html) (general information about Google Analytics and privacy). Please note that, on this website, Google Analytics was extended by the code "gat._anonymizeIp();" to anonymize IP addresses, with the last octet being deleted.

##### Links to Third-Party Websites

The website may link to other websites or resources over which the Vitec Group plc has no control ("external websites"). These links to external websites are not to be understood as an agreement, consent, or recommendation on the part of the Vitec Group plc. By accessing and/or using this website, you acknowledge that the Vitec Group plc merely provides these links and is not responsible for their content. The use of external websites is subject to the terms of use and privacy policies found under the link to the external websites. If you leave our website, we recommend you to be mindful of the fact that you are no longer on the webpages of the Vitec Group plc, and to read the privacy policies of these external websites before disclosing your personal information.

#### Global Customers - Your Rights Under GDPR 

The GDPR May 2018 provides individual rights to EU citizens which are listed below for your convenience. If you are an EU citizen:

  * You have the right to be informed about how we ensure the 'fair processing of your information' and transparency of what we do as stated in this Privacy Policy. 

  * You have the right to access a copy of the personal information we hold about you by making a Subject Access Request (SAR) in writing or by email to SmallHD for attention of the Data Privacy Lead. Full contact details are provided at the end of this Privacy Policy.

  * You have the right of rectification to amend or update your personal information and ensure we maintain accurate and up to date records and or data about you. 

  * You have the right to erasure, also known as 'the right to be forgotten'. The broad principle underpinning this right is to enable an individual to request the deletion or removal of personal data where there is no compelling reason for its continued processing by SmallHD. 

  * You have the right to 'block' or suppress the processing of your personal data. Processing of your personal information may be restricted in the event it is no longer essential to support the use of services provided to you and or not part of any contractual, legal or financial requirement to do so. SmallHD is permitted to store the personal data, but not further process it. SmallHD may retain just enough information about you to ensure that any restriction is respected in future.

  * You have the right for data portability which allows individuals to obtain and or reuse their personal data for their own purposes across different services. It allows you to move, copy or transfer personal data easily from one IT environment to another in a safe and secure way, without hindrance to usability. 

  * You have the right to object to the processing of your personal information based on legitimate interests or the performance of a task in the public interest or exercise of official authority including profiling activity, direct marketing including profiling activity; and processing for purposes of scientific and or historical research and statistics. 

  * You have right to be made aware of any automated decision-making, that made without any human involvement, and or profiling of your personal information by SmallHD. For all Data Protection matters including Subject Access Requests please contact us via email at: [privacy@smallhd.com](mailto:privacy@smallhd.com) ; by phone [+1 (919) 439-2166](tel:+19194392166) ; or in writing - **_118 Mackenan Drive Cary, NC 27511_**.

##### Complaints

If you are unhappy with how we have processed your personal information please firstly contact the Data Privacy Lead listed above ([privacy@smallhd.com](mailto:privacy@smallhd.com)) ; if you are still unhappy you may contact the following: 

  * ###### Information Commissioner's Office (for UK customers) 

Wycliffe House Water Lane Wilmslow Cheshire, SK9 5AF   
Helpline: [0303 123 1113](tel:0303 123 1113) (local rate) or [+44 1625 545 745](tel:+44 1625 545 745)

  * ###### Or (for EU customers)

The European Data Protection Supervisor with online access to its web complaint form at <https://edps.europa.eu/node/75>. 

### Changes to this Privacy Policy

We reserve the right to change this privacy policy at any time in compliance with applicable data protection legislation. If we make significant changes, we will notify you of the changes through our websites or through others means, such as email. To the extent permitted under applicable law, by using our services after such notice, you consent to our updates to this policy. 

We encourage you to periodically review this policy for the latest information on our privacy practices. We will also make prior versions of our privacy policies available for review. 

Last updated on: May 25 2018
